PRODUCT DESIGNER CONTACT

# **Andrew Adams**

www.andrewadams.design andrewjadams3@gmail.com

I'm a product designer with a background in software development, education, and music. I specialize in digital product design and building complex web applications. With four years of industry experience, I love bringing ideas to life through user-centered design.

# **Work Experience**

### PRODUCT DESIGNER

## Narrative Science | Seattle, WA

January 2018 - Present

Day-to-day, I collaborate with product owners and engineers to define the features and user experiences of a next generation Natural Language Generation (NLG) platform.

As a member of small design team, I conduct research, wireframe new ideas, and create pixel-perfect mockups using Sketch. I also lead user tests and interviews to continually improve our products.

I utilize my technical background by developing interactive prototypes using JS/HTML/CSS.

### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

## Narrative Science | Chicago, IL

November 2014 - December 2017

Working closely with designers and back end engineers, I developed an AngularJS web application which now serves over 20,000 users. I also designed and built three extensions for BI tools using React/Redux.

As a front end specialist, I implemented responsive designs for numerous projects using HTML/CSS while maintaining contributions to back end Node and Python development.

#### ASSOCIATE BAND DIRECTOR

## Shawnee Mission North High School | Overland Park, KS

August 2012 - May 2014

I was responsible for conducting rehearsals of a 110-member marching band as well as a 45-member symphonic band. I also instructed 5th and 6th grade band classes at six area elementary schools totaling approximately 120 students.

# **Education**

**BACHELOR OF MUSIC EDUCATION** 

University of Kansas | Lawrence, KS

August 2008 - May 2012

**WEB DEVELOPMENT** 

Dev Bootcamp | Chicago, IL

May - August 2014

# **Skills**

**TECHNOLOGIES** 

JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS, Git

**FRAMEWORKS** 

React, Redux, Angular

**SOFTWARE** 

Sketch, Balsamiq, InVision